<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Central Region Tour App</string>
    <string name="sites">sites</string>
    <string name="hotels">hotels</string>
    <string name="schools">schools</string>
    <string name="festivals">festivals</string>
    <string name="image">image</string>
    <string name="name">name</string>
    <string name="location">location</string>
    <string name="location2">Location:</string>
    <string name="description">description</string>
    <string name="details">Details</string>


    <!--  sites  -->
    <string name="kakumpark">Kakum National Park</string>
    <string name="kakum">Kakum</string>
    <string name="fortamst">Fort Amsterdam</string>
    <string name="kormantin">Kormantin</string>
    <string name="fortwill">Fort William</string>
    <string name="anomabu">Anomabu</string>
    <string name="capecast">Cape Coast Castle</string>
    <string name="capecoast">Cape Coast</string>
    <string name="elminacast">Elmina Castle</string>
    <string name="elmina">Elmina</string>
    <string name="fortpat">Fort Patience</string>
    <string name="apam">Apam</string>
    <string name="fortnas">Fort Nassau</string>
    <string name="moree">Moree</string>
    <string name="fortco">Fort Coenroadsburg</string>
    <string name="fortvic">Fort Victoria</string>
    <string name="fortgo">Fort Goedo Hoop</string>
    <string name="senyaberaku">Senya Beraku</string>
    <string name="kakum_des" >Kakum National Park is on the coast of southern Ghana near Cape Coast in the Central
        Region, in West Africa. It protects an area of rainforest, home to endangered mammals such as forest
        elephants, bongo antelopes and primates like the Diana monkey. The park is rich in butterflies and birds,
        including African grey parrots and hornbills. The Canopy Walkway, suspended 30 meters above the ground,
        provides treetop views of the forest. \n \n
        Area: 375 km² \n
        Phone: 020 042 0831 \n
        Established: 1992
    </string>
    <string name="fortamst_des">Fort Amsterdam, a World Heritage Site is a fort in Kormantin, Central region,
        Ghana. It was built by the English between 1638 and 1645 as Fort Cormantin or Fort Courmantyne, and
        was captured by admiral Michiel de Ruyter of the Dutch West India Company in 1665, in retaliation for
        the capture of several Dutch forts by the English Admiral Holmes in 1664. It was subsequently made part
        of the Dutch Gold Coast, and remained part of it until the fort was traded with the British in 1868. \n \n
        Year built: 1638 \n
        Phone: 055 149 0761 \n
        Inscription: 1979 (3rd Session)
    </string>
    <string name="fortwill_des">Fort William is a fort in Anomabu, Central Region, Ghana, originally known as Anomabo
        Fort and renamed Fort William in the nineteenth century by its then-commander, Brodie Cruickshank, who
        added one storey to the main building in the days of King William IV.  It was built in 1753 by the British
        after they thwarted a French attempt to establish a fort at the same place. Two earlier forts had been
        established at the same site, one in 1640 by the Dutch, another in 1674 (Fort Charles) by the English.
        Fort Charles was abandoned in the late-seventeenth century. \n \n
        Year built: 1753 \n
        Occupant: United Kingdom
    </string>
    <string name="capecastle_des">Cape Coast Castle (Swedish: Carolusborg) is one of about forty \"slave castles\",
        or large commercial forts, built on the Gold Coast of West Africa (now Ghana) by European traders.
        It was originally a Portuguese \"feitoria\" or trading post, established in 1555. However in 1653 the
        Swedish Africa Company constructed a timber fort there. It originally was a centre for the trade in
        timber and gold. It was later used in the trans-Atlantic slave trade. Other Ghanaian slave castles
        include Elmina Castle and Fort Christiansborg. They were used to hold slaves before they were loaded
        onto ships and sold in the Americas, especially the Caribbean. This \"gate of no return\" was the last
        stop before crossing the Atlantic Ocean \n \n
        Construction started: 1610 \n
        Opened: 1653 \n
        Phone: 057 710 1707
    </string>
    <string name="eliminacastle_des">Elmina Castle was erected by the Portuguese in 1482 as Sao Jorge da Mina
        (St. George of the Mine) Castle, also known simply as Mina (or Feitoria da Mina) in present-day Elmina,
        Ghana (formerly the Gold Coast). It was the first trading post built on the Gulf of Guinea, and the oldest
        European building in existence south of the Sahara. First established as a trade settlement, the castle
        later became one of the most important stops on the route of the Atlantic slave trade. The Dutch seized
        the fort from the Portuguese in 1637, after an unsuccessful attempt to the same extent in 1596, and took
        over all of the Portuguese Gold Coast in 1642. The slave trade continued under the Dutch until 1814.
        In 1872, the Dutch Gold Coast, including the fort, became a possession of Great Britain. \n \n
        The Gold Coast, which is now Ghana, gained its independence in 1957 from Britain, and had control of the
        castle. Elmina Castle is a historical site, and was a major filming location for Werner Herzog\'s 1987
        drama film Cobra Verde. The castle is recognized by UNESCO as a World Heritage Site. \n \n
        Opened: 1482 \n
        Phone: 020 179 6793
    </string>
    <string name="forpatience_des">The fort was first built as a stone trading lodge in 1697 at the request of the
        King of Acron, with whom the Dutch had a treaty, and which was situated between the kingdoms of Fante
        and Agona, with whom the British had a treaty. The executives of the Dutch West India Company were quite
        wary to establish a fort in an area with minimal trade, and only consented on the condition that it would
        be built at minimal costs. The Acron were not happy with this, and frequently threatened the Dutch with
        expulsion if they would not extend the fortifications. As a result, it took the Dutch five years to complete
        the building, which is why they gave it the name Fort Patience. \n \n
        By 1721 the lodge had been converted into a defensive fortification, which sat on a craggy peninsula just
        out from the township to the south, offering a commanding view of Apam\'s harbour to the north, and the
        Gulf Of Guinea coast to the south, east, and west. \n \n
        Opened: 1697 \n
        UNESCO World Heritage Site inscription: 1979 \n
        Occupant: Netherlands
    </string>
    <string name="fornassau_des">Located near Moree in the Central Region, Fort Nassau was the first fort built by
        the Dutch due to the unfamiliarity of the Dutch with buildings in the tropics. It was established on what
        became the Dutch Gold Coast and notorious for its unhealthy conditions. \n \n
        The Dutch, in 1624, expanded the fort. \n \n
        Fort Nassau served as the capital of the Dutch Gold Coast from its establishment until 1637, when the Dutch
        captured Fort Elmina from the Portuguese. \n \n
        From 1598 onward, Dutch merchants traded on the Gold Coast of Africa. Although the Gold Coast was already
        settled by Portuguese, there was little effort to evict the Dutch, as the military resources were committed
        to the war in Europe. \n \n
        This changed after the signing of the Twelve Years\' Truce between Portugal-Spain and the Dutch Republic in
        1609. The Portuguese now had sufficient resources to protect their trade monopoly, and began attacking the
        (from the Portuguese viewpoint, illegitimate) Dutch factories on the coast. The factory at Mouri was burned
        to the ground in 1610. Dutch traders then petitioned the States-General of the Dutch Republic to build a
        fort on the coast. The States-General was receptive of their demands, and sent Jacob Clantius, who was to
        become the first General on the Coast, to the Gold Coast in 1611. In 1612, the Treaty of Asebu was signed
        between the Dutch and the chief of Asebu, which allowed for the establishment of Fort Nassau at Mouri. \n \n
        Opened: 1612 \n
        Occupant: Netherlands
    </string>
    <string name="forcoen_des">Fort Coenraadsburg or Conraadsburg, also Fort São Tiago da Mina, is a small Portuguese
        chapel built in honor of Saint Jago and it is situated opposite the Elmina Castle in the Central region of
        Ghana, to protect Fort Elmina from attacks. Fort Conraadsburg was built in the 1660s. It was built on the
        site of a fortified chapel that the Portuguese had built and that the Dutch had burned to the ground in
        the Battle of Elmina (1637). The Dutch ceded the fort to Britain in 1872, together with the entire Dutch
        Gold Coast. Before the fort was built, the Dutch used the hill as a gun-position to bombard the Portuguese
        in the year 1637. To prevent others from doing the same tactic against the Portuguese, the Dutch constructed
        a fortified earthwork the following year. \n \n
        Opened: 1652 \n
        UNESCO World Heritage Site inscription: 1979 \n
        Occupant: Netherlands
    </string>
    <string name="forvic_des"> Constructed in 1821 on the site of a ruined fort built in 1712, Fort Victoria was
        formerly known as ‘Phipp’s Tower’, in honour of its initial constructor English Governor Phipps. It was
        later renamed Fort Victoria after Queen Victoria of Great Britain. \n \n
        Perched on a hill on the western part of the Cape Coast Township in the Central Region, the fort overlooks
        both the Atlantic Ocean and the historic town. Fort Victoria was used as an outlook post for signalling
        purposes. \n \n
        Fort Victoria has been preserved as a monument. The fort is in a respectable condition.
    </string>
    <string name="fordeg_des">Fort de Goede Hoop or Fort Good Hope was a fort on the Dutch Gold Coast, established in
        1667 near Senya Beraku. \n \n
        The Dutch had already had a lodge in Senya Beraku in the 1660s, but that was abandoned when the British
        built their fort at nearby Winneba. In 1704, the Dutch asked the Queen of Agona for permission to build a
        fort at Senya Beraku. It was to serve the gold trade with Akim, which is north of Agona. At first, the
        Dutch built a small triangular fort, that they called Fort de Goede Hoop (or Good Hope in English).
        The gold trade was not very prosperous, but later on slaves were sold at the fort. By 1715, the fort had
        become too small and the Dutch decided to double it in size by breaking away the diagonal and making it
        square-shaped. A slave prison was made in the southwest bastion of the fort. In the second half of the
        18th century, the fort was surrounded by an outer wall. \n \n
        Early in 1782, Captain Thomas Shirley in the 50-gun ship Leander and the sloop-of-war Alligator sailed to
        the Dutch Gold Coast. Britain was at war with The Netherlands and Shirley captured the small Dutch forts
        at Moree (Fort Nassau - 20 guns), Kormantin (Courmantyne or - 32 guns), Apam (Fort Lijdzaamheid or Fort
        Patience - 22 guns), Senya Beraku (Fort Goede Hoop - 18 guns), and Accra (Fort Crêvecoeur or Ussher Fort
        - 32 guns). \n \n
        The fort was occupied between 1782 and 1785 by Britain, as well as by the local Akim population between
        1811 and 1816. In 1868, the fort was ceded to the United Kingdom in a large trade of forts between the
        Netherlands and Britain. \n \n
        Opened: 1705 \n
        Occupant: Netherlands
    </string>

    <!--  hotels  -->
    <string name="oasis">Oasis Beach Resort</string>
    <string name="almond">Almond Tree Guest House</string>
    <string name="rainforest">Rainforest Lodge</string>
    <string name="akrofrom">Akrofrom</string>
    <string name="brenu">Brenu Beach Lodge</string>
    <string name="elminabay">Elmina Bay Resort</string>
    <string name="anomabobeach">Anomabo Beach Resort</string>
    <string name="loreto">Hotel Loreto</string>
    <string name="marrets">Marrets International Hotel</string>
    <string name="oasis_des">Oasis Beach Resort in Cape Coast features accommodations with a garden. Featuring a bar,
        the hotel has air-conditioned rooms with free WiFi and an on-site restaurant. \n \n
        Oasis Beach Resort offers some units with sea views, and some rooms have a balcony. some units will provide
        guests with a fridge and hot shower. \n \n
        Market is 0.6 mi from Oasis Beach Resort. \n \n
        Couples in particular like the location – they rated it 9.1 for a two-person trip.
    </string>
    <string name="almond_des">Located in Elmina, 12.9 km from Elmina Castle, Almond Tree Guest House has accommodations
        with a restaurant, free private parking, a bar and a shared lounge. The property offers car rental and
        features a garden and terrace. \n \n
        At the guesthouse, rooms contain a desk, a TV and a private bathroom. Free WiFi is accessible to all
        guests, while certain rooms are equipped with a balcony. The rooms have a closet. \n \n
        A continental breakfast is available each morning at Almond Tree Guest House.
    </string>
    <string name="rainforest_des">Located in Cape Coast, Rainforest Lodge is a 5-minute drive from the Monkey Forest
        Reserve, a 10-minute drive from Kakum National Park, and a 30-minute drive from the beach. It offers an
        outdoor swimming pool, a garden and free Wi-Fi access. \n \n
        Rooms and suites are air-conditioned and feature a mini-bar, a wardrobe and a seating area with a TV.
        The private bathroom is equipped with a bath. \n \n
        Guests are invited to enjoy breakfast every morning at Rainforest Lodge. They can also enjoy local and
        Chinese dishes in the on-site restaurant. \n \n
        This property has a meeting room and a 24-hour front desk. Massage treatments can be arranged and free
        private parking is available on site.
    </string>
    <string name="brenu_des">Brenu Beach Lodge is set in Elmina, 5 mi from Elmina Castle. Featuring a restaurant,
        the property also features a private beach area. \n \n
        At the resort rooms are equipped with a desk, a TV and a private bathroom. Free WiFi is accessible to
        all guests, while selected rooms here will provide you with a terrace. The rooms will provide guests
        with a fridge. \n \n
        A continental breakfast is available each morning at the property. \n \n
        The area is popular for fishing and car hire is available at this resort. \n \n
        Couples in particular like the location – they rated it 9.4 for a two-person trip.
    </string>
    <string name="eliminabay_des">Located in Elmina, 4.2 km from Elmina Castle, Elmina Bay Resort provides
        accommodations with a restaurant, free private parking, an outdoor swimming pool and a bar. Each
        room at the 2-star hotel has pool views, and guests can enjoy access to a garden and to a terrace.
        The property has room service, a concierge service and currency exchange for guests. \n \n
        At the hotel, all rooms come with a closet. Complete with a private bathroom equipped with a shower and
        free toiletries, all guest rooms at Elmina Bay Resort have a flat-screen TV and air conditioning, and
        selected rooms here will provide you with a seating area. The rooms will provide guests with a desk and
        an electric tea pot. \n \n
        The accommodation offers a continental or à la carte breakfast.
    </string>
    <string name="anomabobeach_des">Located in Anomabo, 5.6 km from Fort Amsterdam, Anomabo Beach Resort provides
        accommodations with a restaurant, free private parking, a bar and a shared lounge. This 2-star resort
        offers a private beach area. The property has a 24-hour front desk, airport transportation, room service
        and free WiFi. \n \n
        At the resort, each room includes a desk. Complete with a private bathroom equipped with free toiletries,
        guest rooms at Anomabo Beach Resort have a flat-screen TV and air conditioning, and selected rooms contain
        a seating area. All guest rooms include a closet. \n \n
        Guests at the accommodation can enjoy a continental breakfast. \n \n
        Couples in particular like the location – they rated it 8.3 for a two-person trip.
    </string>
    <string name="loreto_des">Located 17 mi from Kakum National Park, Hotel Loreto offers accommodations in Cape Coast.
        It features free WiFi and an outdoor pool. Guests can enjoy the on-site bar. \n \n
        Some units have a seating area for your convenience. A terrace or balcony are featured in certain rooms.
        A flat-screen TV with satellite channels is offered. \n \n
        There is a 24-hour front desk at the property. \n \n
        Guests can enjoy various activities in the surroundings, including cycling, fishing and canoeing.
        The hotel also offers bike hire and excursions at a cost. Cape Coast Castle is 6.2 mi from Hotel Loreto,
        while Elmina castle is 21 minutes\' drive away.
    </string>
    <string name="marrets_des">Marrets International Hotel is located in Cape Coast. At the property you will find
        a 24-hour front desk. Free Wi-Fi access is available in all areas. \n \n
        All rooms feature private bathrooms fitted with a shower. Hot tub is provided upon requests. \n \n
        The property offers free public parking at a location nearby. \n \n
        Kotoka International Airport is 93 mi from the property.
    </string>

    <!--  schools  -->
    <string name="mfantsipim">Mfantsipim School</string>
    <string name="wesleygirls">Wesley Girls Senior High</string>
    <string name="augustine">St. Augustine\'s Collage</string>
    <string name="adisadel">Adisadel College</string>
    <string name="apamshs">Apam Senior High School</string>
    <string name="holychild">Holy Child High School</string>
    <string name="mfantsipim_des">Mfantsipim is an all-boys boarding secondary school in Cape Coast, established
        by the Methodist Church in 1876 to foster intellectual, moral and spiritual growth on the then Gold Coast.
        Its founding name was Wesleyan High School and the first Headmaster was James Picot, a French scholar, who
        was only 18 years old on his appointment. \n \n
        Mfantsipim is nicknamed \"THE SCHOOL\" by its old boys for the fact that several other schools in Ghana such as
        Prempeh College were born out of it, as these schools were started with students from Mfantsipim.\n \n
        Founded: April 3, 1876\n
        Motto: Dwen Hwe Kan\n
        Number of students: 2,500\n
        Phone: 024 000 0000\n
        Sister school: Wesley Girls\' Senior High School\n
        Colors: Black, Crimson
    </string>
    <string name="wesley_des">Wesley Girls\' High School, Ghana, is an educational institution for girls in Cape
        Coast, founded in 1836, and named after the founder of Methodism, John Wesley. \n \n
        The school was established in 1836 with 25 girls by the wife of a Methodist minister. It started as a
        primary school with the aim of offering girls training in reading and writing, sewing and house-keeping
        and spiritual development. \n \n
        Wesley Girls\' High School was ranked 68th out of the top 100 best high schools in Africa by Africa Almanac
        in 2003, based upon quality of education, student engagement, strength and activities of alumnae, school
        profile, internet and news visibility. \n \n
        Motto: Live Pure, Speak True, Right Wrong , Follow the King \n
        Founded: 1836 \n
        Number of students: 1,350 \n
        Phone: 050 228 8449 \n
        Staff: 68 \n
        Colors: Green, Yellow
    </string>
    <string name="augustine_des">St. Augustine\’s College is an all-male academic institution in Cape Coast, Ghana.
        The school started at Amissano, a village near Elmina, in 1930. The Roman Catholic institution was
        established to serve as a training college and seminary. The school was named after St. Augustine of Hippo
        (354 – 430 AD). The motto of the college is Omnia Vincit Labor, meaning "\Perseverance conquers All\".The
        school has a total of 11 houses. \n \n
        St. Augustine\'s is the first catholic institution in the training of male teachers. It is also the first
        catholic second cycle school (senior high school) to be built in Gold Coast, (now Ghana). St. Augustine\’s
        College is the biggest catholic senior high school in Ghana to date. The college ground and playing fields
        cover an area of about 1.30 acres. It is bounded by Fosu Lagoon/Adisadel Estates to the North, St.
        Augustine’s Practice J.H.S., the Catholic Education Unit and Archbishop’s House to the West, the Cape
        Coast metropolitan Hospital and part of the Fosu Lagoon to the East and the Atlantic Ocean to the South.
        It is about 1.8 km from Cape Coast Town Hall (Bakaano) and about 2.3 km from the West gate of University
        of Cape Coast. The school has a student population of about 1,900 and a faculty number of about 90. \n \n
        On 6 August 1933, the Roman Catholic Church and the Bishop of Cape Coast Vicariate Monsignor W. T. Porter
        felt the need to have a separate Roman Catholic school and Cape Coast was found to be the most suitable
        location. A commemorative foundation stone was laid in late 1935 at the present site. Fr. Maurice B.
        Kelly, the Dean of the Training College at Amissano which is now St. Teresa’s Seminary, Amisano, became
        the first Head Dean or Headmaster. \n \n
        Motto: Omnia Vincit Labor \n
        Founded: 1930 \n
        Number of students: 2,000 \n
        Phone: 033 213 2733 \n
        Mascot: Hippo \n
        Affiliation: Catholic Church \n
        Staff: 82 \n
        Colors: White, Green
    </string>
    <string name="adisadel_des">Adisadel College, popularly known as "\ADISCO\", is an Anglican boys\' boarding
        school in Cape Coast, Ghana. Key aspects of the school\'s administration and curriculum were originally
        modelled on the English public school system during the colonial era. The present curriculum falls within
        the Senior High School system in Ghana, with overall oversight by the Ghana Education Service. The word
        "\Adisco\" is a portmanteau of "\Adisadel\" and "\College\". The school is named after what used to be a
        small village on the outskirts of the Cape Coast township - Adisadel Village. In recent times, the village
        has expanded considerably and gradually merged imperceptibly with the main township. It is now a sprawling
        urban suburb with vibrant commercial activities. Adisco and Adisadel Village share direct boundaries, with
        the former occupying the hilly landscape and part of the adjoining low-lying area. It is commonly
        acceptable to use the name of the village (Adisadel) in reference to the school. \n \n
        Adisadel College was ranked 10th out of the top 100 best high schools in Africa by Africa Almanac in 2014,
        based on quality of education, student engagement, strength and activities of alumni, school profile,
        internet and news visibility. \n \n
        Founded: 1910 \n
        Phone: 033 213 2543 \n
        Number of students: 1,500 \n
        Founder: Temple Hamlyn \n
        Mascot: Zebra \n
        Colors: Black, White
    </string>
    <string name="apam_des">Apam Senior High School is a coeducational senior high school at Apam in the Gomoa
        West District of the Central Region of Ghana. \n \n
        Apam Secondary School, in the Zone B District of the Central region of Ghana, was established in 1953
        at Paado\'s plains, a suburb of Apam (a coastal town in the area). The school had a very humble beginning
        under a cocoa shed and oak trees. It started under the management of Rev. deGraft-Johnson as a day school
        with Mr. C.S Arthur Hesse as the only teacher. \n \n
        In 1960, the school relocated to its present site, Mbofra mfa Adwen, with a very grand and impressive
        opening ceremony performed by Lord Listowel, the last Governor of the then Gold Coast, now Ghana. The
        development of the school that led to the adoption of the name Great Apass was achieved under the
        leadership and aegis of the late Dr. Peter Augustus Owiredu otherwise known as PAO. Dr. P.A Owiredu took
        over as the headmaster from Rev. degraft-Johnson in 1959 to 1981(?). \n \n
        By 1964, the school had moved from a day school to a boarding school and had introduced advanced Level
        subjects in the Arts and Sciences in addition to the Ordinary Level courses it offered. \n \n
        Founder: Joseph W.S. de Graft-Johnson \n
        Founded: February 20, 1953 \n
        School district: Gomoa \n
        Colors: Green, Yellow \n
        Alumnis: David Dontoh, Ato Quayson
    </string>
    <string name="holychild_des">Holy Child School, also known as Angel\'s Hill, is a female second-cycle
        institution in Cape Coast in the Central Region of Ghana. In 2003, the school was ranked among the best
        10 schools in Africa, producing the best overall female student in the 2003 Senior Secondary School
        Certificate Examinations (SSSCE) Holy Child School also produced the best overall student,Jochebed
        Adwoa Sutherland and the second best overall student, Audrey Emefa Awuttey for the 2017 West African
        Senior School Examination, WASSCE. It was founded by the Society of the Holy Child Jesus (SHCJ)
        in the year 1946 to provide education to Catholics within the region.The current student population stands
        at over 1000 girls aged between 14 and 18 years. All students of Holy Child School are boarders. The School
        has always prided itself in providing holistic education for females so that they may strive to achieve
        higher heights and become \"Women of Substance\". The school motto is \"Facta Non Verba\" which simply
        means Actions Not Words. The present headmistress of the school is Rev. Sister Josephine Anto, commonly
        known as \"JoJoy\" or \"Joezzy\" Their colours are yellow and brown. \n \n
        Founder: Society of the Holy Child Jesus \n
        Founded: 1946 \n
        Phone: 4232104 \n
        School district: Cape Coast Metropolitan \n
        Colors: Yellow, Brown
    </string>

    <!--  festivals  -->
    <string name="aboakye">Aboakye Festival</string>
    <string name="winneba">Winneba</string>
    <string name="masquerading">Masquerading Festival</string>
    <string name="bronya">Edina Bronya</string>
    <string name="bakatue">Edina Bakatue Festival</string>
    <string name="akwambo">Akwambo Festival</string>
    <string name="agona">Agona</string>
    <string name="panafest">Panafest</string>
    <string name="odwira">Odwira Festival</string>
    <string name="jukwa">Jukwa</string>
    <string name="afahye">Fetu Afahye</string>
    <string name="okyir">Okyir Festival</string>
    <string name="aboakyir_des">The festival is a celebration to mark the migration of these people from the ancient
        Western Sudan Empire where they were led by 2 brothers and a god called Otu. Upon consulting their god, they
        were instructed by their traditional priest or mediator between the people and the god to sacrifice a young
        member of the Royal family every year to their god. \n \n
        This was not good news so they made an appeal to their god who asked for an animal from the wildcat family
        to be caught alive and beheaded before the god. \n \n
        Before the festival began they settled the god at a place called Penkye hence the god became Penkyi Otu.
        When the people went out to hunt down the wild cat they lost so many men before capturing it alive. This
        caused the second appeal. Penkyi Otu decided to accept a mature bushbuck this looks like a deer. \n \n
        The people of Simpa sang this story in their war chants and told it during moonlit nights. It was kept and
        protected till it could be written in English for all to read. \n \n
        Today, the Aboakyir festival is celebrated in May each year and is a major event in Ghana.
    </string>
    <string name="masquerading_des">It started around the 1920\’s and is celebrated on the 1st of January every year
        and draws large crowds from all over. \n \n
        There are four fancy-dressing groups who participate in the festival competition, wearing masks and accompanied
        by brass band music. The festival begins in the morning of New Year Day with street dancing and is open to all
        the performing groups who parade through the principal streets of Winneba. \n \n
        The groups converge at the Advanced Teacher Training College Park where the competition takes the form of
        a march past and three different dances (Highlife/Blues) performed by the groups. \n \n
        A team of judges award marks and at the end of the day the most versatile group is crowned the winner.
    </string>
    <string name="bronya_des">This festival is a novel Christmas introduced to the people of Elmina during the Dutch
        era of the colonial period. The period coincides with the Dutch Festival which falls on the first Thursday
        of January every year and marked in Elmina to signify the bond of friendship between the Dutch and the people
        of Elmina. \n \n
        A fish-catching ritual is performed at the banks of the Benya Lagoon by the Asafo Companies in their full
        regalia. The Paramount Chief and his retinue are present at the banks and musketry is fired. On the eve of
        the festival, the Paramount chief climbs up Fort SI. Jago and fires shots at midnight to usher in the New
        Year. The Paramount Chief rides in a Palanquin the next day to pay homage to the various clans. \n \n
        Libation is poured using locally prepared wine and there is sprinkling of mashed yam as well as shaking of
        hands with family heads to signify peace, prosperity and good health in the coming year. The paramount Chief
        and his elders converge in front of Elmina Castle where a sheep is slaughtered. There is merry-making drumming
        and dancing throughout.
    </string>
    <string name="bakatue_des">Literally translated means \“The opening of the Lagoon\” or \"the Draining of the Lagoon\”.
        It is celebrated to commemorate the founding of the town, Elmina by the Europeans. It is also celebrated to
        invoke the deity, Nana Benya’s continuous protection of the state and its people. \n \n
        During the celebration, the Paramount Chief and his sub-chiefs, elders\’ fetish priests and priestesses, and
        indeed the entire state offer the sacred food of eggs and mashed yam mixed with palm oil to the river god
        and prays for peace. \n \n
        All rituals are performed on Mondays. Fetish priests and priestesses and drummers take turns to perform their
        rituals. There is a performance of the spiritually possessed chief fetish priest as he responds to spiritual
        revelations. \n \n
        There is royal possession made up of gorgeously dressed chiefs and stool carriers, some riding in beautifully
        decorated palanquins. After performing some rituals at the riverside, the chief priest casts his net three
        times and announces the lifting of the ban on fishing, drumming, funerals and other social activities in the
        traditional area. \n \n
        There is a spectacular ride on the lagoon by women resplendent in \“Kente\” cloth and local festive headgears.
        A royal procession leading to the chief’s palace amidst traditional music ends the festival
    </string>
    <string name="akwambo_des">The people of Agona in the Central Region celebrate the festival literally meaning
        \“path-clearing\”. The Asafo companies weed footpaths leading to the streams or rivers, farms and other
        communal places, as well as paths, which lead to shrines. The following day, the whole community assembles
        at the ancestral shrines and the chief pours libation to the ancestral spirits to thank them for their
        protection during the previous year and then request for more blessing, abundant rainfall and good harvest
        for the ensuing year. At the stream or riverside where some of the sacrifices are offered, alligators and
        other species of fish come out to enjoy the mashed yams sprinkled on the water. \n \n
        With their bodies smeared with clay, the people then parade with twigs and tree branches through the town
        in groups amidst drumming, dancing and firing of musketry. \n \n
        In a procession, they go through the principal routes and then to the durbar ground to meet the chief and
        his elders. \n \n
        There is a vigil kept at night and patronized mainly by the youth. It is a time when people come together
        to renew family and social ties. Performing groups, which are dormant are revitalized and new groups
        initiated.
    </string>
    <string name="panafest_des">Pan-African Historic Festival is a major biennial event of cultural forum for Africans
        and people of African descent as well as friends of the continent committed to the noble cause of Pan
        Africanism. \n \n
        The venues for the Panafest are the historical towns of Cape Coast and Elmina. The festival is a celebration
        of African cultural values, history and civilization. This consists of:
        \*performances and workshops in theatre, drama, music, cinema, poetry, colloquia and lectures. \n
        \*colourful traditional durbar of chiefs and people of Ghana \n
        \*tours/excursions to places of interest such as the slave castle dungeons. \n \n
        Panafest brings together participants from all over the world.
    </string>
    <string name="odwira_des">The Odwira Festival, which is celebrated by the Denkyira people, runs for weeks,
        beginning at Jukwa, the traditional capital, and ends at Dunkwa-on Offin, the administrative capital. It
        signifies cleansing or bathing their ancestors and lesser gods. Drumming and firing of guns are done to
        announce the festival in the palace. There is wailing and weeping by the women amidst the firing of guns
        by the Asafo companies. Its significance is to remember the departed. \n \n
        On Friday, the two Asafo Companies (traditional warriors) joined by the inhabitants, take to the streets
        of Jukwa amidst drumming and dancing. Later the Chief is carried in a palanquin to a sacred place where
        sacrifices are made to departed royals of the Denkyira State. \n \n
        The festival in Jukwa ends with a durbar of chiefs and people of the area. After the first week in Jukwa,
        the festival is moved to Dunkwa-on Offin, the administrative capital for the climax of the festivities.
    </string>
    <string name="afahye_des">The most attractive aspects of Ghanaian cultural life are that of the colourful
        traditional festivals and durbars which are frequently held in all part of the country. \n \n
        Festivals reveal some common features, during these festivals; the people remember there past leaders and
        pray for help and protection. Festivals are also held in order to purify the whole state so that the people
        can enter the New Year with confidence and hope. \n \n
        Fetu Afahye is being celebrated by the people of Oguaa or Cape Coast Traditional Area in the Central Region
        is named after the 17th Century Fetu or Effutu kingdom which is located 19 kilometres inland of Cape Coast.
        This festival starts on the 1st of September every year, features of this festival is the state purification
        rites which includes the paramount Chief’s Yam festival and is observed in the form of offering mashed yams
        to the gods. \n \n
        The festival is very colourful and it\’s like a grand festival there is a processing of chiefs, drumming,
        dancing and firing of musketry but this is uniqueness in the traditional attire of the various warrior groups
        and the slaughtering of a cow in public for the 77 gods of Oguaa (Cape Coast). \n \n
        There is also a display of traditional priests and priestesses on Monday night, which attracts large crowd
        mainly the youth and thousands of people including foreigners from all over the country travel to witness
        the festival. This festival has effect of creating in the people a feeling of pride in their cultural heritage
        and spiritual affinity. \n \n
        During this occasion it also gives people the opportunity to meet old friends and relatives they\’ve missed
        for a long time. \n \n
        But there is another significant feature ceremony \“Bakatue\” involves cutting through the sand bar separating
        the Fosu lagoon and the sea to allow the lagoon access into the sea presumably to bring more fish into the
        lagoon. \n \n
        The Omanhene (Paramount Chief) as part of the event, pours libation to the deity, Nana Fosu, Omanhenes\’ net
        is cast three times into the lagoon to signify the lifting of the ban on lagoon fishing. \n \n
        Various fishermen\’s groups in the municipality organize a regatta or board race on the lagoon. A grand
        Durban climaxes the festival.
    </string>
    <string name="okyir_des">Okyir is the major festival celebrated by the people of Anomabu. It is celebrated as a
        sign of cleansing or purification of the town from filth, evil spirits etc. \n \n
        Highlights of the festival include the following activities: \n \n
        \• A yam festival celebrated by offering food to the 77 gods of the town. \n
        \• Vigil keeping. \n
        \• Preparation and distribution of food among friends and loved ones. \n
        \• A colourful durbar of chiefs. \n
        \• Beach programme. \n \n
        The climax of the Okyir is on the second Sunday of October
    </string>

</resources>
